Guide to the Florencio Asenjo Collection, 1945-2013 UA.90.F105
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Undated Compositions, II.
  - Three Images From Don Quijote, 22.
    Instruments: For chamber orchestra: Flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Bass Clarinet, Bassoon, Trombone, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, Double bass, and Timpani.
    I. The enchanted barque; II. I am coming to be executed; III. Don't die señor Don Quijote.
    - Manuscript score (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Full score manuscript copy (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Printed score (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Printed parts (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Ubiquities: A Symphony of Contrasts, 23.
    Instruments: Orchestra: Flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, Trumpet in C, Trombone, Timpani, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, Double bass.
    I. Andante; II. Moderato; III. Andante. Note on p. 84 of full score: Duration 22'13" Date in the sketch of the Choral: "9/6/46"
    - Full score manuscript (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Full score manuscript copy (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Printed full score (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Printed director score (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Printed parts (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified sketches, 1955-2002 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Three different sets of unidentified drafts that were written between 1955 and September 28, 2002. Date on set number 1 "6-4-55". Dates on each page of set 2 [from "August of 2001" to "September of 2002"]. The third set is a draft of a string quintet. Contains indications and comments by the composer.
  - Jaime Pahissa: Monodia Para Orquesta, 1927 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Instruments: Orchestra: Piccolo, 2 flutes, 2 Oboe, 2 Clarinets in B-flat, 2 Bassoons, Contabasson, 4 Horns in F, 3 trumpets in C, Tuba, Timpani, 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, and Double bass.
    Composition of Jaime Pahissa (1880-1969), dedicated to Manuel Roviralba "en testimonio de una vieja amistad" [as a testimony of our old friendship]. Dedicatory to Florencio Asenjo in the foreword "A mi querido Florencio, como buen amigo y excelente discípulo: Jaime Pahissa" [To my dear Florencio, as a good friend and excellent disciple: Jaime Pahissa].
- Articles, III.
  - A Phenomenological Analysis of Stravinsky's "Threni", 1963 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Article published in the quarterly Forum, summer-fall of 1963.
    - Correspondence with the magazines, 1.
    - Correspondence with Igor Stavinsky (includes two Stravinsky autographs), 2.
  - Polarity and Atonalism, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Article published in Journal of Aesthetics and Art Criticism, 1966, pp. 47-52
    - Original typescript, 1.
    - Correspondence, 1965-1966; 2.
    - Article reviews, 1967; 3.
  - The Aesthetics of Igor Stravinsky, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Article published in the Journal of Aesthetic and Art Criticism, Spring 1968.
    - Original typescript draft, November 19, 1966; 1.
    - Article review, August 14, 1964; 2.
    - Correspondence, 1966-1968; 3.
    - Correspondence with Igor Stravinsky (includes two Stravinsky autographs), 4.
  - The Generation of Form by Geometric Methods, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    This article was presented at two conferences: "Centro de Ingenieros Provincia de Buenos Aires, Julio de 1954", and "The Ohio State University, 1970."
    - Typescript draft, 1.
    - Original typescript, 2.
    - copy of typescript, 3.
    - Four negatives of the images of the text, 4.
    - Abstract, 5.
    - Conference typescript, 6.
    - Correspondence, 1969-1972; 7.
  - The Crisis in Western Music and the Human Roots of Art, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Published by the Journal of Aesthetics and Art Criticism in 1971.
    - Typescript draft, 1.
    - Correspondence, 1971-1972; 2.
  - The Principle of the Contemporary of All Styles, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Article published in Soundings (Vanderbuilt University), Fall 1975 p. 381-389.
    - Orginial draft, 1.
    - Finished version, 2.
    - Published version, 3.
  - Maximalism and Minimalism, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    Article published in Penn Sounds. Volume 10, No. 2, Winter 1999, p. 3-4.
    - Manuscript, 1.
    - Printed article, 2.
    - Correspondence, 3.
- Music and Academic Production, IV.
  - Newspaper clippings and reviews, 1953-1965 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Arts Week, La Plata, Argentina, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    The National University Eva Peron [Actual National University of La Plata]—where Florencio Asenjo was professor—and the Ministry of Education organized this arts festival in 1954. Florencio Asenjo was a member of the committee that created the program. Florencio Asenjo also participated in the Festival with the lecture "Simetría y polaridad en las matemáticas y en las artes" [Symmetry and polarity inmathematics and arts].
  - Correspondence with Carl Fischer, Inc., 1965-1972 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Music scores information (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Contract for production with Kirk Trevor, 2008 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Music recordings indexed in Records International, 2004-2008 (Box 26, Folder 13)
- Personal Documents and Correspondence, V.
  - Jaime Pahissa, 1938-1977 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Foreign travels, 1959-2009 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Ernesto and Manuel Halffter, 1963-2012 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence regarding a cancelled competition for String Orchestra Works, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    Material related to a cancelled Eastman String Orchestra Competition in 1989, the material indicates that this was a polemical issue that involved a scam.
  - Correspondence with Harry Hewitt, 1990-2002 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with the American Music Center, 1991-2003 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Draft of a radio program, January 27, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    Transcript of a program in the Latin American Radio Magazine [Revista Radial Latinoamericana] at WRCT, CMU Radio. Giovani E. Reyes, Martha E. Mantilla and Victor Cordova produced this radio program. The family also donated some tapes with the recordings.
  - Peer review of an article by Donald B. Parker sent to the Journal of Musicological Research, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, 1953-2008 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Manuel de Falla and Jaime Pahissa, presumedly in Córdoba, Argentina, 1.
    - Florencio Asenjo conducting the strings of La Plata Symphonic orchestra, El Teatro Argentino, La Plata, Argentina, October 11, 1953; 2.
    - Florencio Asenjo and Kirk Trevor during the recording with the Bohuslav Martinu Philharmonic Orchestra, c. 2008; 3.
- Audio Recordings, 1954-1972; VI.
  - Symphony for Strings, LRA Radio Nacional, 1954; 1.; 1 reel-to-reel (Box 28)
  - Concerto for Wind Instruments, U.S. Air Force Band, Harry Meuser, conductor, January, 1960; 2.; 1 reel-to-reel
  - Concerto for Wind Instruments, Master tape, Eastman Wind Ensemble, A. Clyde Roller, conductor, April 30, 1964; 3.; 1 reel-to-reel
  - Danza de los Secretarios, Eastman Philharmonic. A. Clyde Roller, conductor, April 21, 1965; 4.; 1 reel-to-reel
  - Concerto for Wind Instruments, Duquesne University Symphonic Band, John Wilson, conductor, November 23, 1975; 5.; 1 reel-to-reel
  - Danza de los Secretarios, Duquesne University Orchestra, undated; 6.; 1 reel-to-reel
  - Symphony No. 2, first movement, rehearsal, 7.; 1 reel-to-reel
  - Excerpts from Cavalcade of Cubes; Danza de los Secretarios; Concerto for Wind Instruments; Symphony for Strings, 8.; 1 reel-to-reel
  - Cavalcade of Cubes, undated; 9.; 1 reel-to-reel
  - Side 1: Cuarteto [Quartet]; Side 2: Bodas de la Montaña [Mountain Weddings], Obertura [Overture] by Jaime Pahissa, 10.; 1 reel-to-reel
  - Side 1: Sinfonía Segunda [Symphony No. 2]; Side 2: Suite Intertonal, 11.; 1 reel-to-reel
  - La Atlantida [Atlantis] (opera) by Manuel De Falla, 12.; 3 reel-to-reel
  - Suite Intertonal by Jaime Pahissa, 13.; 1 reel-to-reel
  - Los Gozos de Nuestra Señora [The Joys of Our Lady] by Ernesto Halffter, 14.; 1 reel-to-reel
  - Side 1: Elegía [Elegy]; Side 2: Two Psalms by Ernesto Halffter, 15.; 1 reel-to-reel
  - Radio Interviews, Argentina, 1972; 16.; 14 cassette_tapes
  - Radio Interviews, Argentina, 1972; 17.; 2 reel-to-reel
  - Symphony for Strings, Buenos Aires State Radio Orchestra, 1954; 18.; 3 discs (Box 29)